rgsommer777@gmail.com

Mobile & Text: (678) 310-7045

An experienced IT servant leader who drives successful, high value technology projects and programs. I thrive in high-change, uncharted environments and bring effective, proven Agile, Scrum and Kan Ban techniques to establish consistent, predictable delivery. I place a high value on team collaboration; fully activating the necessary diversity of thought to achieve the best and most creative solutions to business challenges.

SKILLS

- Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)
- Experience with SAFe 4.0 (working on SAFe 5.0 cert.)
- Strategic Enterprise Program Implementation
- Business development processes
- Exceptional facilitation skills
- Resource and Scope Management (Jira/Confluence, Clarity PPM, VersionOne, MS Project)
- 5+ years experience in Jira & VersionOne
- Experience working with virtual teams across multiple time zones in Skype, Zoom, MS Teams
- Highly effective strategist with experience leading analytical resources on projects
- 10+ years coaching / motivating /mentoring teams and individual team members (formal + informal)

- KPI's, measurements, metrics, Business intelligence
- Experience working in an enterprise Agile environment
- Educator & Trainer (Estimation, Risk Management)
- Large scale enterprise data conversions
- Influence without authority via accountability
- Craft and deliver executive presentations to C-Level and Senior Management
- Experience in high growth, complex environments
- 15+ years experience in waterfall SDLC transitioning to Lean to Agile/Scrum
- Continuous learner focused on driving continuous organizational improvement

EXPERIENCE

Analytics/Experimentation Program Manager / Macy's / 02/2019 – 02/2020

Served as Program Mgr./Scrum Master for digital experimentation on the macys.com site and app. Collaborated with Product Managers and Analysts to develop methods and tactics to prioritize and manage "air traffic control" over multiple in-flight experimentation efforts.

- Facilitated development of an online system for Macy's digital product organization and product analysts to track and manage development and retrospective analytics review
- Resolve conflicts between product management team and analysts to prioritize and deliver highest value experiments and feature ramping efforts
- Provided visibility to experiment status tracking and repository for results and recaptured resource time previously spent chasing experiments status and results from disparate tools and data sources

Enterprise Portfolio Manager / Macy's / 07/2015 - 02/2019

Created the methodology, system and tool set to lead teams through scoping and estimation activities, feeding into the strategic portfolio decision making process. Leading application development related efforts and ongoing activities at the enterprise level to define scope and budget estimates (both capex and opex), plus benefit and/or cost reduction analysis in order to determine best investment position and placement within corporate IT strategy.

 Integrated Excel worksheets with MS Sharepoint and Nintex workflows to streamline enterprise process for collecting and assessing estimates across over 130 teams involving technology, product, finance and management.

- Responsible to develop new products, solutions and platforms for recommendation of valid solutions
- Delivered enterprise budget estimates for Macy's and Bloomingdale's technology portfolios totaling up to \$20mm annually.

Senior Enterprise Program Manager / Macy's / 11/2012 - 06/2015

Original member of the Enterprise Program Management Office (EPMO). Guided teams through the process of establishing common best practices and preparing for Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI) certification to comply with Sarbanes-Oxley requirements with highest standards of quality.

- Created risk management process, supporting documentation and training program for Macy's software development teams with a focus towards continuous improvement.
- Certified as CMMI Professional

Enterprise Program Manager / Macy's / 06/2007 - 11/2012

Planned and managed programs for various internal technology delivery teams such as enterprise portal, marketing, financial systems.

- Managed program to build Macy's first web-based portal in IBM WebSphere
- Key program manager responsible for 40 person cross-functional team of stakeholders to design, build and test Macy's Loyalty system on the TIBCO platform, producing program schedules, milestones and develop and deliver change management strategies in a fastpaced, team-driven environment.
- Converted key learnings on Macy's Loyalty combined with new business requirements from Bloomingdale's to create their Loyallist® customer loyalty platform.

Program Manager / Macy's / 03/2002 - 06/2007

Drove overall program to build the first Enterprise Data Warehouse for Macy's. Managed multiple subteams to load the initial data objects from sales, receipts and orders into the new Teradata warehouse. Collaborated with other Program Managers through several mergers and acquisitions to represent and manage activities in those vertical areas as part of the overall enterprise initiative.

- Primary role to manage program deliverables, engaging directly with Senior Leadership solving issues and mitigating risks on high priority initiatives
- Delivered four key data conversion projects for business critical financial systems as part of \$11B May Company Acquisition
- Developed effective strategies and collaboration with key stakeholders supporting technology operations

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Georgia Institute of Technology - Atlanta, GA Bachelor's Degree: Electrical Engineering

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM®) Six Sigma Black Belt (NCR) Certified CMMI Professional